Guide to the Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Reference Collection, 1963-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Reference collection 1963-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.0 Linear Feet approx. 300 Items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives from a variety of sources.
Historical Note
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, the University's largest undergraduate college, was formed in 1972 by a merger of Trinity College for Men (usually just called "Trinity College") and the Woman's College. "Trinity College" is the most common usage, with "Arts and Sciences" added on, as in the phrase "Arts & Sciences and Trinity College." The administrative structure has varied over time. For example, there has been a Dean of Arts and Sciences, and a separate Dean of Trinity College. At present, the college's chief officer is called "Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences and Dean of Trinity College."
Collection Overview
The TCAS Reference Collection contains published materials including newsletters and brochures, lists, handbooks, and clippings, and memoranda from the Deans. It includes some material from Arts & Sciences prior to the formation of TCAS. Among the subjects are curricular programs for first-year students, the role of the Director of Undergraduate Studies, faculty publications, editors of journals, and house courses, and information for parents.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Clippings, circa 1976-1990 (Box 1)
  - Dining with Students, 1989
  - The Duke Experience: A Sampling from the Arts and Sciences, 1984
  - First Year Seminars, 1988-199
  - FOCUS Program, 1989-
  - FOCUS Program Brochures, 1995-
  - Handbook for Directors of Undergraduate Studies, 1986
  - Handbook for Parents, 1995-1997 [classes of 1999-2001] (Box 2)
  - House Courses, 1969-1991
  - Memoranda, 1963-1983
  - Parents' Newsletter, 1994-1998
  - Publications: Miscellaneous